片名：塘鹅暗杀令
堕胎就是谋杀
救救孩子们
皮革代表死亡
罗森伯该死
标语上有我名字吗?
Any of those signs got my name on them?
还不少
Quite a few.
都写些什么?
What do they say?
陈腔滥调
The usual.
罗森伯该死、
"Death to Rosenberg."
罗森伯下台
''Retire Rosenberg.''
切断氧气管
''Cut off the Oxygen.''
我最爱这句
That's my favorite.
你也不错  葛瑞先生
Of course   you   Mr. Grantham...
上次在报刊痛批我
...did pretty good by me your last time out.
罗森伯代表政府操控经济
''Rosenberg equals the government over business...
人治胜于法治、
''...the individual over government
环境主宰一切
the environment over everything...
至于印地安人
''...and the lindens   oh
就放他们一马吧
give them whatever they want.''
不是我说的
With all due respect   that wasn't my line
是引用别人的话
that was a quote.
出自某位匿名白宫高层官员
From one of your unnamed Senor White House officials.
应该说是白宫高层混蛋
Senor White House bastard   you should have sad.
他有今天的地位
Got in there by...
全靠挑拨离间
...stirring up these people   one against the other.
人为了跻身白宫
Never fails to amaze me...
手段真是无奇不有
...what a man will do to get an oval office.
谁?
Yes
史奈尔先生在吗?
Looking for Mr. Sneller.
史奈尔先生?
Mr. Sneller?
是的  艾德温史奈尔
yes   Mr. Edwin F. Sneller.
你好
Hello
一切都安排好了
Everything is in place.
我到苏黎士前要拿够钱
All the money must be there when l arrive in Zurich.
事情办妥  钱就是你的
it will be there if the job is finished.
别担心
It will be finished.
我能效劳吗?
-May l help you?
你好  我想叫吃的
-I'd like to order room service.
您想吃什么?
-What would you like?
咖啡、
-Coffee...
煎蛋、全麦吐司、柳橙汁
...scrambled eggs   whole wheat toast and orange juice   please.
15分钟后送到
It'll be about 15 minutes.
谢谢!
Thank you very much!
当我们用威胁取代辩论、
When we substitute threat for an argument...
施暴取代讲理
...violence for principle
就是任由情绪
we allow our passion...
主导了理性
...to overcome our capacity for reason.
但这种私人情绪常危害自由
Passion and self-interest are threats to liberty...
以"乔治亚州哈维克例"来说
...which brings us to Bowers against Hardwick.
警方去他公寓
A police officer entered Mr. Hardwick's apartment
递传票
to serve him a warrant...
罪名是违法公然饮酒
...for an unpaid violation for drinking in public.
警方抓到他光天化日喝啤酒
They caught him with an open beer.
当警官进房时
When he entered Mr. Hardwick's bedroom...
发现他和一个男人在床上
...he found him in bed with a man.
他当场抓人
The officer arrested Hardwick...
因为该州禁止男人性交
...for violating Georgia's statute which outlaws sodomy.
州政府随后撤销了控拆
Even though Georgia dropped the case...
但哈维克却反控
...Hardwick challenged
该法令违反宪法?
the constitutionality of the statute.
告诉我  他凭什么?
Now   what was his clam?
你说
Yeah
该法令侵犯隐私权
That it violates the right of privacy.
为何?
Why?
哈维克有权在家中为所欲为
He's got the right to do as he pleases in his home.
若在家中贩毒、
But what if he decided to sell drugs at his home
或虐待儿童呢?
or engage in child abuse?
这些行为不属隐私权的范畴
Those actions don't fit within the right of privacy.
最高法院大法官格利渥认为
The court   beginning with Griswold...
隐私权
has limited the right of privacy to
限于个人
actions which are intimate...
亲密行为
...which are deeply personal
是旁人无法介入的私人空间
which allow us to control our lives...
宪法有这么写吗?
But is that a constitutional clam?
宪法并不
There's no...
界定何谓私人空间
...right to define oneself written into the Constitution.
权利法也不提过
it's not even in the Bill of Rights.
若乔州有权干涉
lf the State of Georgia can regulate Hardwick's sexuality
成人私下从事的自愿性行为
...engaged in private with consenting adults
哈维克就不可能获释
Hardwick cannot be free.
州政府的权力要受宪法限制
The Constitution ensures limited government.
若不是隐私权这个护身符
lf there's no right of privacy
而乔州仍按常法判刑
and Georgia can enforce the statute...
就牺牲了宪法
we sacrifice the liberty the framers
保护人民的自由
thought they'd guaranteed us.
但最高法院并不这样想
The Supreme Court disagreed with you.
他们不认为该法
They found that the statute did not
侵犯隐私
violate the right of privacy.
那怎办?
Why is that?
死不认错
Because they are wrong.
凌晨1点  获知罗森伯法官
They found Rosenberg around 1 A.M.
和他看护皆被枪杀
Hs nurse was also murdered.
2小时后  杰生法官的尸体在戏院被发现
Jensen was found two hours later in some queer club.
FBI局长伏尔来电时口气沮丧
Voyles called me   wildly upset.
这对FBI打击很大
it's hardly good for FBl's reputation.
他和格明斯基马上就到
He and Gminsk are on the way.
CIA局长格明斯基?
Gminsk?
对  这节骨眼上应让CIA参与
ClA should be involved   at least for now.
若要观众开机
You must wait two hours to
要等到7点  您再向全国发表谈话
address the nation if we want an audience.
穿西装、打领带显得排练过
A coat and tie may seem a bit rehearsed.
穿毛衣吧
How about a cardigan?
国家出现危机之际
you want me to talk to the nation
你要我穿毛衣对人民讲话?
in a time of crss wearing a sweater?
总统先生
Mr. President...
已通知司法部
...l've already told Justice to
提出名单
put together a list of nominees.
重整法院是你的责任
Restructuring the court will be your legacy.
总统先生
Mr. President.
伏尔  FBI找到嫌犯了吗?
Mr. Voyles   does the FBl have any suspects?
没这么快
it's too soon.
稍后会提出凶器和验尸报告
We'll have ballistics and autopsies later.
我要一份安检报告
l would like to have a report on your security
看是那里出了问题
and where it broke down.
您认为安检有漏洞?
you're assuming it broke down.
死了两个法官
We have two dead judges
还死在FBI的保护下
both of whom were being protected by the FBl.
鲍伯  我要实情
Bob   I'd like a straight answer.
这些谋杀和CIA有关吗?
Are these killings in any way linked to the ClA...
或和任何
...or to any other agency of the
政府单位有关吗?
United States government?
你这么想  我很吃惊
I'm shocked you'd think that.
鲍伯  调查一下  好吗?
Bob   just look into t   okay?
我建议5点再回到这里讨论
l suggest we meet back here at five.
各位  5点  谢谢
Five o'clock   gentlemen. Thank you.
该发动形象保卫战
it's rally-around-the-leader time.
人民对你的支持率会激升
your approval ratings will go through the roof.
以上是纽奥尔良天气情况
That's the weather in New Orleans. This is Tim Bellew.
本节目现插入特别报导
We interrupt our program now for a special bulletin.
白宫特别记者会实况报导
in a special address   live from the White House...
美国总统发表讲话
...the President of the United States.
亲爱的同胞们
My fellow Americans...
我国遭受了一项重大损失
...our country has suffered a grievous loss.
昨晚
Last night...
最高法院罗森伯和杰生法官
...Supreme Court Justices Rosenberg and Jensen...
遭暗杀身亡
...were assassinated.
这些暗杀行动
These assassinations
可能企图打击
may be an attempt to strike at the very fabric...
我们政府
...of our government.
但我向公民们保证
But l can assure each and every American
我们不会坐视这种卑鄙行为
...that these dastardly acts will not go unpunished.
调查
Everything...
行动已全面展开
...s being
凶手将被绳之以法
and will be done to bring the culprit...
正义必须、
...or culprits to justice.
也必然
For justice must...
得到伸张
...and shall prevail.
亚特兰大转机入口处
可惜我当他秘书时  你不认识他
l wish you could have known him when l used to clerk for hm.
上次见他时  他只剩脑袋管用
Last time l saw him   only the mind was left.
这就是他被杀的原因
That's why they killed hm.
他的头脑仍构成威胁
That mind was still a threat.
何必杀他?他已时日无多
But why kill him now when he had so little time left?
怕他活到
Maybe they couldn't take a chance
下次大选吧
he'd last till the elections.
杰生又为何被杀?他是当今总统提名
So why Jensen? This President nominated hm.
和罗森伯几乎没共同点
He and Rosenberg had almost nothing in common.
几乎  不是完全没有
Almost.
调查单位应该找一下
That's what they should look for.
他俩所共同支持的法案
decisions on which they both agreed.
唉  若这时能喝上两杯多好
Boy   if there ever was a moment for a drink....
一天只准一次  对吗?
One day at a time   right?
若这是个阴谋
We're talking a conspiracy
谁是主谋?
then who are the conspirators?
若是让国外恐怖份子潜入?
lf we've let foreign terrorists in
我们会付出惨重的政治代价
there'll be hell to pay politically.
情治单位不能
The intelligence community can't be
替移民局背黑祸
blamed for a weakness in migration.
丹顿
Denton...
你想是谁做的?
...who are your suspects?
这件事务必保密
This has to be kept very quiet.
当然  这是总统办公室
Of course. This is the Oval Office.
在华府  至少
At least
有11名恐怖份子
11 Underground Army members have been in the DC area...
他们至少涉嫌
...and we suspect them in at least
百件爆炸案
100 bombings of abortions clinics...
包括堕胎诊所、色情场所、同性恋俱乐部  遍及全国
...porno houses   gay clubs all over the country.
说穿了  你不知是谁干的
The truth s   you don't have a suspect.
对吧?
Correct?
华府"前锋报"的葛瑞一向负责采访
Gray Grantham has been covering the
最高法院
Supreme Court for the Washington Herald.
你曾访问过他
you actually interviewed Justice Rosenberg...
罗森伯法官遇害当天
...before he was shot on   as it turned out   the day he died.
他是否说过什么话
did he say anything that
可能透露出惨案的原因?
might shed some light on these dreadful events?
是  说了一些
yes. He spoke about things...
现任法官非公开的私人意见
...off the record   appropriately for a sitting Justice.
不过  现在引述应该无妨了
But l think it would be appropriate to quote him now.
他说
He sad
总统的竞选手段无情
The campaign waged by the President was ruthless...
看重中产阶级
in its manipulation of the meddle-class fears of minorities
对于少数民族的恐惧感  剥削离间
''...had been so exploitative and divisive that
造成了互不信任气氛
it created a climate of distrust.''
这个葛瑞真是深得我心
you know   that Grantham's a man after my own heart.
大家都问你何时再开课
Everyone wants to know when you're starting classes again.
我也不知道
That includes me.
有人说  酒入愁肠愁更愁
you know what they say drinking makes depression worse.
那他们建议如何减轻苦恼?你最近去那了?
What do they recommend for anguish? Where've you been?
图书馆
The library.
研究一份最高法院的判法摘录
l studded a printout of the Supreme Court docket.
顺便也列了一份嫌犯名单
l even made a list of possible suspects.
后来扔了它
And then threw it away
因为没新意
because they'd be obvious to everyone.
随后
Then
你找两位死者的共通处?
you looked for areas Jensen and Rosenberg had in common.
正是
Exactly.
杰生一般比较偏袒
Jensen generally protected the rights of
刑事案被告人
criminal defendants.
这有点意思
Some notable exceptions.
他还提出3项
He wrote 3 majority opinions
环保意见
protective of the environment.
并支持抗税人
And almost always supported tax protesters.
很可能被
So they might have been assassinated by
贪婪的税官暗杀
an insatiable tax collector?
目前为止  每人都有嫌疑
As yet   l rule no one out.
根据我的假设  大家以为动机是仇杀、报复
Everyone is assuming the motive s hatred or revenge.
或企图影响法院的社会议程
Or an attempt to influence the social agenda of the court.
但也许搞了半天  只是为个利字?
What if the issue involved old-fashioned material greed?
牵涉大笔金钱?
A case that involves a great deal of money?
我能为你效劳吗?我想看这个档案
-Can l help you? -I'd like to see this file   please.
为何?
Why?
这是公开的记录  不是吗?
it's public record   isn't t?
半公开
Sem-public.
你听过"资讯自由条例"吗?
Are you familiar with the Freedom of information Act?
这份档案包括诉状、
This file has the pleading...
答辩状
...and correspondence.
还有强制公开文件、审判记录
The rest s discovery and the trial.
审判是何时?
-When was the trial?
去年夏天
-Last summer.
持续了两个月
-Went on for 2 months.
上诉状呢?
-Where's the appeal?
还没提出  期限是8月1日
Not perfected yet. l think the deadline is August 1st.
谢谢
Thank you
说吧  谁干的?
So   who done it?
你的嫌犯名单会让
you have some obscure suspect unknown to the
FBI、CIA、及
FBl and the ClA and...
所有的警察眼红
...Secret Service and 10  000 police departments?
是有一份
l had one...
但我不打算用
...which l have now discarded.
你逃课一周不理我
you skipped class   ignored me for a week
到头来把报告扔了?
just to throw it away?
给我瞧瞧
Let me see t.
别笑
don't laugh.
我真以为自已破了案
it was ludicrous of me to think l could solve t.
女福尔摩斯  是吧?
Hubris of the young   huh?
还真自负呢
don't knock the hubris that l love.
我明天启程
I'm leaving tomorrow.
去华盛顿参加罗森伯的告别式
I'm gong up to Rosenberg's memorial in Washington.
这几晚读了些他审理的案件
l went through Rosenberg's decisions the other night...
突然有个构想
...and in the back of my mind there's an idea...
想为他写本书
...to do a book on hm.
你是最佳人选
No one could do it better.
我从锁事写起
l started making notes...
到他待我如师如父之情
...about what he meant to me surrogate father   mentor
你知道
you know.
然后  我就想喝杯酒
l started to get very thirsty.
这周真是冷落你了
l deserted you this week.
我真不会选时间
Not the greatest timing.
你是来学法律  不是当我保姆
You're here to study law   not keep me sober.
我是爱丽思
it's Alice.
想不想去吃汉堡?
Want to come out with me for a burger?
不了  谢谢
No   thanks
出去透透气  对你有益
it might do you good to get out.
我很好  谢谢
I'm fine   thanks.
你确定?
you sure?
好的  再见
Ok   goodbye
嘿  士官长
Hey   Sarge.
嘿  小子
Hey   son.
咖啡、加奶、三颗糖
dark coffee   three sugars.
老总好吗?
So how's the President?
哪一个?
Which one?
不是冠尔  是正牌总统
Not Coal   the real one.
气定神闲呢
Cool and mellow.
你以为他真会为罗森伯烦恼?
Would you believe he's all tore up about Rosenberg?
那么费神地
And all fried up about...
重整最高法院、
...restructuring the court.
希望能青史留名
Thinks it'll make his place in history.
听起来倒像寇尔  有消息吗?
Sounds like Coal. What'd you get me?
有几个候选人
There's a short list of nominees.
原有20个
The original had 20 or so names
他们删成8个  我给你两个名字
then they cut it to 8. l gave you 2.
调查进行得如何?
What about the investigation?
没听说什么
l haven't heard much...
我会留意的
...but I'll keep my ears open.
我知你会  谢了
-l know you will. Thanks.
我请客
-l got that.
谢了  再见
I'll see you later.
要气定神闲啊
Mellow   mellow   mellow.
白宫拟定法官候选人名单
一杯马丁尼
Martin   please.
早  真高兴见到你
Good day. Good to see you.
再来杯咖啡
Another coffee   please.
你看了葛瑞写的报导吧
you read the Grantham article.
就是它弄得我忙了一天
it had me running around all day.
寇尔炮轰FBI头子
Coal blasted the director
说他们泄漏法官名单人选
saying the judges' names were leaked by the FBl.
FBI则反咬寇尔一口
The director sad Coal had
说他自已放风声、测风向
leaked them himself to test the waters.
寇尔搞离间是20年来罕见
Coal ran the most divisive campaign n 20 years...
总统却坐视不理
...and the President did nothing.
我很高兴见到你名列法官候选人
I'd like to have seen your name on this list of judges.
你的呼声最高
You're the one we all voted most likely to make the Court.
这年头  光是教书就够辛苦了
These days   it's hard enough just to make my class.
这一次这女孩几岁?
How old is she   this time?
24岁  但是她……
Twenty-four. But she's...
非常成熟
...extremely mature.
24岁  很成熟?
At twenty-four   she's mature.
我不信  有照片吗?
l don't know if l believe that. do you have a photo?
没有  她又不是小狗或乖孙
No   l don't. She's not a puppy dog or a grandchild.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
是谁杀了他们?
Who killed them   Gavin?
我只是局里的律师  又不是情报员
I'm just a lawyer with the Bureau   I'm not an agent.
可我记得你一向耳聪目明
But   as l recall   you have great ears.
说实话  我们毫无头绪
To be honest   we don't have a clue.
我女友写了一份有趣的报告
My girlfriend wrote a very interesting essay...
是有关谁可能下令暗杀
...on who might have ordered the assassinations.
你女友有一套追凶定律?
your girlfriend has a theory?
拿去看吧
Here   take a look at it.
你会喜欢她的脑袋
you'll get a kick out of the way her mind works.
格雷葛瑞吗?
-is this Gray Grantham?
是的
-yes   it is.
很抱歉这时打扰
Sorry to call at such a crazy hour.
我是在上班路上打的公用电话
I'm at a pay phone on my way to work.
不能在家里或公司里打
l can't call from home or the office.
什么公司?
What kind of office?
我是个律师
I'm an attorney.
私人还是公家?
Private or government?
不便说
I'd rather not say.
我有……罗森伯和杰生案的线索
l may know something about Rosenberg and Jensen.
你在录音吗?
Are you recording this?
没有
No
这电话会被追查吗?
Can this call be traced?
我保证没录音、也没追踪
I'm not recording it or tracing it. l promise you.
我也许知道是谁杀了他们
l may know who killed them.
贵姓大名?
What's your name?
贾西亚
Garcia.
这不是真名吧?
That's not your real name.
不  我在办公室看
l think l saw something at the office
到不该看的东西
l wasn't supposed to see.
你有副本吗?
do you have a copy?
这点我要保留一下
l need to think about this.
我了解
-l understand.
我没有想得很清楚 我明白
-I'm not thinking rationally.
听着  我向你保证
Listen   l promise you...
我会保密你的身份
...l will protect you as a confidential source.
喂?
Yeah
哈罗?
Hello
逮到你了
Got you.
喂?
Yeah
葛瑞不在
Mr. Grantham's not here
他留了手机号码给你
but he left his car number for you.
格雷葛瑞?是的
Grantham? Yeah
我是贾西亚  我还是拿不定主意
l still don't know what to do.
贾先生
Mr. Garcia...
我宁可坐牢  也不泄露消息来源
...I've gone to jail rather than reveal a source.
我知道你不好受
l know what kind of hell this must be for you.
显然你是个正派的好国民
y you're clearly a decent human being   a good citizen.
但你能昧着良心
But could you live with yourself if
不说实话吗?
you don't reveal what you know?
我再打给你
I'll get back to you.
的士
Tax
法国当局在
French authorities reviewed footage from
机场安检录影带中  发现一人
the airport cameras in Pars...
可能是
...and think they recognized a face that
恐怖份子凯莫
might be Khamel's   the terrorist.
他已抵达华盛顿
He may have arrived here on a flight 10 hours after
在杰生法官被杀之前  他就抵达了
we found Jensen's body.
还有什么消息?
Anything else?
或许有个小小的新发现
Maybe a small new wrinkle.
什么新发现?
What's the wrinkle?
是一份报告  出炉不到一天
it's a theory that surfaced n the last 24 hours.
伏尔对它很感兴趣
Voyles is really intrigued by t.
他担心报告对总统不利
He's afraid it might be damaging to the President.
怎么说?
How's that?
你看了就知道
it's all there in the brief.
联邦调查局"机密勇敢正直"
这是外行人写的
it's amateur stuff...
但何时寇尔会被报告
...but how often does something
搞得冒汗
make Coal sweat and run for cover?
虽然他没真的冒汗
He didn't exactly sweat in front of us.
但紧绷的脸看得出他不高兴
But his stone face showed he wasn't happy.
总统生了什么病?
did he have any symptoms?
我说过
As l told you
总统是做例行体检
the President is here for his annual checkup.
我希望自已像他一样健朗
l wish l was in as good shape.
选这时体检  是怕选举时扯出年龄问题?
Was this timed to counter the age issue in the next election?
我怎么没想到?
Why didn't l think of that?
他还没决定是否竞选
He hasn't decided whether to run again.
他何时决定?
When will he decide?
你真的要我回答吗?
do you really expect me to answer that?
我只能说
One rumor l can deny is that
他住院不是为躲你们
he checked in to get away from you.
就算是  又怎么怪他?
Although could you blame him?
再次感谢 谢谢你
Thank you again. Thanks
去通知他们
Commander   go downstairs and tell them
下午我要打高尔夫球
l have a date for golf this afternoon.
遵命
yes   sir
你如此健康  让媒体无题可作了
it's killing the press you're so healthy.
那好啊  何事这么重要?
Good. Now   what's so important?
这是
This's...
一份报告摘要
...a brief...
一个用功过度的法律系学生写的
...written by an eager-beaver law student.
是关于暗杀的推论
it's a theory about the assassinations.
间接
And indirectly...
影射白宫
...it implicates the White House.
虽然荒谬且无知
The premise is so farfetched it's absurd.
但伏尔局长正着手调查它
But director Voyles
个中原因你我都猜
for reasons both you and l can guess...
得到
is going after it
哦  能不能……
Well   could we....
我想我们不能干涉调查
We can't interfere with his investigation.
你应该要格明局长从CIA角度调查
you should ask Gminsk to have the ClA investigate.
只要证明这玩意胡扯
When we confirm that this is garbage
就可令伏尔停止调查
you can ask Voyles to back off.
但这是国内案件
it's domestic.
CIA无权插手  这是违法的
The ClA can't go nosing around. it's illegal.
只是技术上的问题罢了
Technically.
你那位朋友  巴尔及"特派小组"  我想你找过他了
...Barr   and the Unit   l think you call t.
我和巴尔已谈过
I've spoken to Barr.
他们精于小型特殊任务
They're very good for small specific missions...
但他们不是CIA
...but they aren't the ClA.
它怎么影射白宫?
How does it implicate the White House?
有指名道姓吗?
What are there   names?
提到一个名字
One name.
我们都认识的?
Someone we both know?
我已决定我的人生规划  我要待在床上
I'll stay in bed...
饮酒
...drink...
做爱
...make love...
把这件狗屎事情抛之脑后
...and forget the whole damn business.
你不同意?
You don't approve.
不是要替罗森伯写书吗?
What about the book on Rosenberg?
应该你写
you should write it.
走吧 不  你应该写的
-Let's go. -you should.
你年轻、有能力、又坚定
you have the youth   the energy   the certitude.
你是最佳人选
you'd be perfect.
锁匙给我吧
Can l have the keys?
我绝对能开车的
I'm perfectly capable of driving.
你喝多了
you've drunk too much.
锁匙给我
Give me the keys.
还记得60年代的芋泥吗?
-do you remember the Mashed Potato?
不记得了  锁匙给我吧
-Give me the keys.
你太年轻了 我知道
You're too young. -l know t.
记得回波舞吗?
Do you remember the Fishback?
滑舞?不记得  拜托你
-The Slide? -No. Please.
拜托什么?
-Please what?
给我锁匙
-Give me the keys.
我开车  不然我走路回家
Give me the keys. I'll drive or I'll walk.
你要走路回家?是的
You'll walk? Yes
祝你散步愉快
Have a nice stroll.
萧小姐
Mss Shaw
你让我神魂颠倒
you take my breath away
汤姆士
Thomas
噢  天啊  天啊
Oh   my God
小心车门
Watch the door.
我是纽奥良警局巡佐  鲁伯特
I'm Sergeant Rupert   NOPd.
你在我车上不会有事
you'll be safe in my car.
大名?
your name?
黛比萧
Darby Shaw.
我们走
Let's go.
这是你的车吗?
is this your car?
这边  巡官
Come here.
我是欧森  纽奥良警局
I'm Lieutenant Olsen   NOPD.
我现在送你去医院
I'm taking you to the hospital.
查一下车牌
Check the plates.
你认识车上那个人?
did you know the man in the car?
汤姆士可拉汉
Thomas Callahan.
医生待会就来
it'll be a few minutes.
你确定……
Are you sure that the man who
那个鲁伯特自称是警察?
called himself Rupert sad he was a cop?
是的
Yes
我们没有叫鲁伯特的警察
We don't have a record of a cop named Rupert.
电脑
The computer...
查不出
...has no record of the tag
那车牌
numbers of the car you were in.
必是假的
Must be fake.
我去把车弄走  马上回来
I'll go move the car. I'll be back.
好吗?
All right?
喂
Hello
葛文维西?是的
Gavin Verheek? Er yeah
我是贷比萧  知道我是谁吗?
This is Darby Shaw. do you know who l am?
知道  我们有共同的朋友
We have a mutual friend.
汤姆士给过你一份我的报告?
Thomas gave you a copy of my theory.
是的
yes   he dd.
报告在哪?
Where is t?
我看过后  拿给局里的人
l read it and l showed t to some folks at the Bureau...
他们交给伏尔局长了
...who sent it to director Voyles.
有没有FBI以外的人看过?
Has it been seen outside of the FBl?
我不能说  黛比
l can't answer that.
那我也不说汤姆士出了什么事
Then l won't tell you what's happened to Thomas.
好吧  是的  报告流出FBI
it's been seen outside the FBl
但不知谁看过
but by whom l don't know.
他死了  葛文
He's dead   Gavin.
被谋杀的
He was murdered.
车上装了炸弹
Someone planted a car bomb for both of us.
我侥幸没死  对方正在找我
l got lucky   but they're after me.
你电话号码?你在哪?
What's your phone number? Where are you?
慢点
Not so fast.
别这样  汤姆士是我至友
Come on Thomas Callahan was my best friend.
等15分钟  我找探员去接你
I'll have agents pick you up.
你呆在街上太危险
you can't stay on the street.
汤姆士之死是因跟你谈过
Thomas is dead because he talked to you.
把这话告诉伏尔
Tell that to Voyles.
电视开大声点  我听不见
Turn up the TV   l can't hear Regis and Kathie Lee.
总统先生
Mr. President.
坐  瞧瞧
St down. you must see this.
我们练习了一上午
We've been working on this all morning.
第一次作秀
you have your first audience.
翻  过去
Over. Roll over.
翻过去
Roll over.
那份报告调查得如何?
How serous is this Pelican thing?
已派出14名探员
I've assigned 14 agents in New Orleans.
我怀疑它的真实性
l doubt if there's anything to t
但要查明
but we must check it out.
不必我提醒你
l don't have to tell you...
万一媒体得到风声
...how much trouble and pan this nonsense could cause...
这事会惹出大麻烦
...f the press gets wind of it.
不错  至少你表演了半套
Oh   well   you got half of t. Good boy.
我只希望
l just wish...
你能放手
...that you'd...
停止追查此事
...back off the thing....
我觉得
l mean...
那纯粹是捕风捉影
It's a goose chase.
你是叫我放过嫌犯?
Are you asking me to ignore a suspect   Mr. President?
万一媒体
If the press...
听到风声  新闻一炒作
...gets wind of what you're after and starts digging
我可就……
I'll be--
我们都会毁了
We'll be crucified.
所以你要我停止追查?
So you're asking me to back off?
停止调查  去追真正的凶手
Back off and chase the real suspects.
暂时搁置几周罢了
ignore it for a few weeks   that's all.
你的人串通媒体
your hatchet man did a real number on me with the press.
攻讦保护
They ate my lunch over
两位法官的安全措施  让我下不了台
the security we provided Jensen and Rosenberg.
叫他别惹我
Get that pt bull off my ass and
我就暂且搁置
I'll forget the Pelican theory a while.
您的信用卡?
May l have your card?
我付现金
I'll pay with cash.
维西?是的
Vocky? Yes
伏尔怎说?
What did Voyles say?
他一直没空
Mr. Voyles has been unavailable.
今天下午我会设法跟他谈
But l will try to speak to him later this afternoon.
我以为你很积极
l expected more.
明天有个告别式
There's a memorial service tomorrow.
晚上我会过去
I'll be there tonight.
我们应该见个面
l think we should meet.
黛比  我能救你
Darby   l can save your life.
你连见局长都办不到
you can't even talk to the director.
你会住哪里?
Where will you stay?
威士敦  靠河边那家
At the Westin   by the river.
好
Ok
她在看电视
She's watching TV.
他们找错地方了  她若用信用卡
They've been looking under rocks. She's using credit cards.
绝对活不过48小时
She'll be dead in 48 hours.
我赌72小时
I'll give her 72.
6点见
We'll meet at 6 A.M.
好
All right.
胡腾  你留下
Hooten   stay.
这表示她的报告推论正确
This means her little brief s right on point.
你会通知总统吗?
Will you notify the President?
总统若知道
Notifying the President...
寇尔就知道了
...means notifying Coal.
葛瑞的文章明天见报
Gray Grantham's article n tomorrow's Washington Herald...
他提到
...maintains that
某白宫匿名人士透露
according to unnamed White House sources...
中东恐怖份子凯莫
...the Mid-Eastern terrorist   Khamel...
可能是暗杀
...may be among those who assassinated
罗森伯、杰生的凶手
Justices Rosenberg and Jensen.
幕后主使者
Those sources say that
可能是某个支持恐怖活动的国家
a country known for sponsoring terrorist activity...
是贾西亚 你好
it's Garcia.
我在宾州大道和第一街的街角
I'm on the corner of Pennsylvania Avenue and First.
好的  记下我车牌
Take down my license number;
街上富豪车多 行
there's a lot of gray Volvos out there.Ok
8-5-6
8-5-6...
V-N-N
...V-N-N.
8-5-6-V-N-N
对了 好的
Right. Ok
10分钟后见 好的
Ten minutes. Yeah
车匙
My keys
我办不到
l can't do t.
我们见面再说
Let's get together anyway.
见个面你会安心
you'll feel better if we meet and
你可以不说
you don't have to reveal anything.
我有老婆小孩
l have a wife and daughter.
他们可能发现我知道了
There's a chance they know that l know.
你是指公司那些人?
The guys at the firm?
不  我没说我在公司上班
l didn't tell you l was in a firm.
你上班太早  不可能是公家律师
you go to work too early to be a government lawyer.
你们公司一定要求员工
you must work at a firm where they expect people...
一周上班至少100小时
...to work at least 100 hours a week.
贾西亚
Garcia
见个面必能解决问题
we can work this thing out f you just get together with me.
贾西亚?
Garcia?
那位?
Who's this?
请问是格雷葛瑞吗?
is this Gray Grantham?
没错  你是哪位?
yes. Who's this?
你知道塘鹅档案吗?
Have you heard of the Pelican Brief?
什么案?
The what?
塘鹅档案
Pelican Brief.
没有  从没听过
Never heard of t.
是有关
it's an unlikely little theory about
罗森伯、杰生命案的凶手
who killed Rosenberg and Jensen.
我朋友准备把它带到华盛顿
A friend of mine took it to Washington.
交给FBI的一个朋友
He gave it to a friend in the FBl
但走漏风声
and it was passed around.
我朋友被炸死在车里
My friend was killed in a car bomb.
且慢……
Wait now.
把它拿给FBI的朋友
Your friend took it to the FBl...
然后被杀?这朋友叫什么名字?
...and then he was killed? What's his name?
不能说
l can't tell you that.
你又怎么知道这些?
How do you know all this?
东西是我写的
l wrote the brief.
你是律师?
Are you a lawyer?
不是
No
你从哪打的电话?
Where are you calling from?
你别再问了
I'd rather you not ask me any more questions.
是你打电话给我……
You called me.
对不起  你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
爱丽思 是你打电话给我  爱丽思
-Alice. -you called me   Alice.
你能
Can you
弄到竞选献金大户名单吗?
get a list of the major presidential campaign contributors?
可以  明天就能拿到
Yes. Sure. l can have it tomorrow.
你知道凶手是谁?
You know who did these killings?
对
Yes
别兜圈子  是谁杀的?
Let's cut to the chase. Who did t?
别急  我们会再联络
Let's take it slow. I'll be in touch.
何时?
When?
塘鹅档案、不是律师、法律系学生?不叫爱丽思?
你好吗?
How are you?
你呢?
你去我公寓了吗?
did you get into my apartment?
你的电脑不见了
your computer's gone.
磁盘也没了
So are your floppy disks.
红色活页夹也被拿了
And your red expandable files.
我要你帮我个忙
l need you to do me a favor.
明天去参加告别式
Go to the memorial service tomorrow...
放话
...and spread the word l called to say
说我住在丹佛姑妈家
I'm staying with an aunt in Denver.
秋天才回
And l won't be back until fall.
到底怎么回事?
What is gong on?
钱够用吗?
Are you okay about money?
有  老爸留下的
l have the money my father left me.
你在躲谁?
Who are you hiding from?
你快走吧
l think you better go now   Alice.
你快走我才安心
it would be better for me if you go now.
真不公平啊
That's not far.
这地方最漂亮的女孩
The prettiest girl in the Quarter
却最悲伤
the saddest girl in the Quarter.
不能对我笑一笑?
l can't get you to give me a smile?
我看到了
l saw that.
暂且算它是笑吧
That's something.
喝杯啤酒?不要
Just one beer?
我找到人生的目标了
I've found my mission in life.
就是让你微笑
To make you smile.
你另找目标吧
you must find another mission.
等一下……
Wait
嫁给我吧  5分钟就好
Will you marry me   just for 5 minutes?
我认为我们是
l know it's stupid   but l think we're
天生一对
fated for each other.
我要走了
l must go now.
拜托  你不会这样甩掉我吧?
Please   you're not gong to walk out on me   are you?
我走遍千山万水
I'd walk a million miles
只求佳人一笑
For one of your smiles
美丽、
you beautiful
美妙的女孩子
you wonderful girl
来自洗衣店
From the laundry
你找错人了
you've got the wrong girl.
去追她
Go get her.
请帮我
Please   help me
谁?
Yes?
找史奈尔先生
Looking for Mr. Sneller.
史奈尔?
Mr. Sneller?
对  艾德温-史奈尔
yes   Mr. Edwin F. Sneller.
有黛比的消息吗?
Have you heard from Darby?
有啊
yes   l dd.
她有留言
l got a note from her.
她住在科罗拉多的姑姑家
She's staying with an aunt in Colorado.
下学期就回来
But she's gong to be back next semester.
再见
I'll see you later.
葛文  我是黛比
Gavin   it's Darby.
我以为你不再联络了
I'd just about given up on you.
说个地点  我带3名探员过去
Tell me where you want to meet and I'll come with 3 agents.
我以为FBI会插手
l thought the FBl was not involved.
还没插手  但我有朋友
it's not involved   not yet. l have friends.
今晚就能送你出城
We can get you out of the city tonight
明天到华盛顿
in Washington tomorrow.
我保证你会见到伏尔
l promise you'll meet Voyles.
然后再看情形而定
We'll go from there.
明天中午  搭电车到河道区
At noon tomorrow   take the trolley to Riverwalk.
河道区?
Wait   Riverwalk?
对  你穿长袖衫、戴红色棒球帽
Wear a long sleeve shirt and a red baseball cap.
在河边的乐台等我
Wait on the riverside at the bandstand...
我会去找你
...and I'll find you.
河边的乐台?好的
The riverside bandstand.
你有多高?
-How tall are you?
5尺10寸
-5' 10''.
体重?
your weight?
l80磅  正打算减肥
About 180   but I'm planning on losing t.
明天见吧
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天见
Tomorrow.
葛文  我是黛比
Gavin   it's Darby.
我以为你不联络了
I'd just about given up on you.
说个地点
Tell me where you want to meet and
我带3名探员过去
I'll come with 3 agents.
我以为FBI会插手
l thought the FBl was not involved.
还没插手
it's not involved   not yet.
但我有朋友
l have friends.
今晚就能送你出城
We'll get you out of the city tonight
明天到华盛顿
in Washington tomorrow.
我保证你会见到伏尔
l promise you'll meet Voyles.
然后再看情形而定
We'll go from there.
明天中午  搭电车到河道区
At noon tomorrow   take the trolley to Riverwalk.
河道区?
Riverwalk?
对  你穿长袖衫、戴红色棒球帽
Wear a long sleeve shirt and a red baseball cap.
在河边的乐台等我
Wait on the riverside at the bandstand and
我会去找你
I'll find you.
河边的乐台?好的
The riverside bandstand?
你有多高?
-How tall are you?
5尺10寸
-5' 10''.
体重?
your weight?
l80磅  正打算减肥
About 180 but I'm planning on losing t.
好的
All right.
说个地点……
Tell me where you want to meet....
说个地点
Tell me where you want to meet...
1小时内  我会带3个探员过去
...and within an hour I'll come get you with 3 agents.
史奈尔先生在2线
Mr. Sneller on line 2.
凯莫死了  不知道谁干的
Khamel is dead. We don't know who did t.
那女孩呢?
-And the girl?
跑了
-She's running.
追丢了  我们会找到她
We lost her. We'll find her.
又多一件谋杀案
There's been another murder.
我曾对你提过
you remember l sad
我朋友把东西交给FBI的朋友
my friend gave the brief to a friend at the FBl?
对
Yes
FBI的朋友昨天被杀了
The FBl friend was killed yesterday.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
我当时握着他的手  他被枪杀
l was holding his hand. He was shot...
光天化日之下  周围都是人
...in broad daylight in a crowd.
我很遗憾
I'm very sorry.
我在纽约  你何时能来?
I'm in New York now. When can you come?
你要给我点东西  让我证实
you'll have to give me something l can confirm.
很多人都来电
We get many calls from people
声称知道真凶
clamming to know who killed Rosenberg and Jensen.
你能证实的消息?
Something you can confirm?
是的
Please.
举个例子
Such as?
被炸死在车里的那个朋友的名字
The name of the friend that was murdered in the car explosion.
你考虑一下
Take your time.
可拉汉
Callahan.
他的名字?
Hs first name?
汤姆士
Thomas.
发生地点?
Where did it happen?
纽奥良
in New Orleans.
这些够了吧?
l think that should be enough.
好的
All right.
FBI那个朋友的名字
What's the name of the friend that worked at the FBl?
维西
Verheek.
葛文维西
Gavin Verheek.
伏尔的首席辩护律师
Voyles' Chef Counsel.
够多了吧?
l think that's more than enough.
我搭下午的飞机
I'll be on a plane this afternoon.
你必须照我的指示
you must follow my instructions.
你好
Hello
我是格雷葛瑞
This is Gray Grantham.
没错
That's right.
知道了
Got it
你是照我指示来的?
did you follow my instructions?
是的
Yes
你一定以为我疯了
you must think I'm crazy.
本来是的
yes   l did...
直到我向纽奥良查证
...till l checked New Orleans.
可拉汉确是
Callahan was...
被炸死
...killed exactly
和你所说一样
as you sad.
我还查了维西
l also check on Verheek.
FBI称
According to the FBl...
两天前的凌晨
...they found his body 2 days ago...
在酒店房间发现他的尸体
...in a hotel room early in the morning.
已死亡至少8小时
He'd been dead for at least 8 hours.
不可能
That can't be.
你愿谈谈档案的事吗?
Want to talk about the brief?
所有谈过档案的人都死了
Everyone I've told about the brief is dead.
我赌赌运气
I'll take my chances.
你无论如何不能使用我的本名
you can't   under any circumstances   use my name...
透露消息来源、
...or reveal how you got the information.
或刊登报导  直到我离境
Or publish anything until I've left the country.
同意吗?
Agreed?
或者我能说服你改变心意
Unless l can convince you otherwise.
不可能
you can't.
我能坐下吗?
May l sit down?
能录音吗?
Mind if l use a tape recorder?
内容很有趣  不是吗?
interesting read   isn't it?
总统看法如何?
What'd the President say?
他和伏尔谈过
He spoke to Voyles...
伏尔愿意暂时搁置调查
...who will leave it alone for a while.
总统叫伏尔不管?
The President asked Voyles to back off?
原来我们以为只是捕风捉影
We thought it was just another shot n the dark.
现在我不敢说了
Now I'm not sure.
这是干涉司法
That's obstruction of justice.
若档案内容属实
Assuming the brief turns out to be true.
若属实  你会成箭靶
lf it does   you'll be the fall guy.
倒霉的不会只有我
l won't be the only one.
用尼克林那两招转移目标
The old Nixon two-step.
别提那个名字
don't even think that name.
往好处想  两伊军火案都没事
Look at the hopeful side   Irangate   Iraqgate....
也许实情不会曝光
Good chance it won't come out.
葛瑞在干什么?
What's up with Grantham?
我们只弄到他的汽车电话
We got his car phone.
还没进他家
We haven't been inside the home yet.
为何?
Why not?
正巧碰上清洁女佣在他公寓里
We almost got caught by the cleaning lady.
他知道"塘鹅档案"的事
Grantham knows about the brief.
他今天致电给3名白宫幕僚
He called 3 White House aides today...
天知道打给谁了
...and God knows who else.
是什么引你注意这件案子?
What made you hone n on this particular case so quickly?
一年前  头条新闻
l remembered this piece that ''Frontline''
曾报导过
did a year ago...
该案的原告律师无故自杀
...about the young lawyer who originally fled the suit.
大家说他自杀
They sad he'd committed suicide
但家人认为是他杀
but his family thought it was foul play.
后来  我和他家人联络
After the assassinations   l called his family.
He needed governmental permission...
他们说  他是有多年的忧郁症
They sad he had a depressive problem years before...
但药物已经控制病情
...but medication had taken care of t.
医生也同意家属的看法
Hs doctor confirmed what the family sad.
他们告诉警方
They told the police
不相信是自杀
they were not convinced it was suicide.
但警方结案了?
But the police closed the investigation.
没错
Exactly.
就这些  这就是档案内容
That's t. That's the brief.
明早再谈  好吗?
Maybe we could finish up in the morning?
我想连夜整理笔记
I'll stay up and go over my notes...
趁现在记忆犹新
...while they're fresh in my head.
你醒来再打电话给我
Call me when you wake up.
好的
Ok
睡一下
Try and get some sleep.
葛瑞先生
Mr Gray Grantham
别见笑
l know it sounds silly   but...
可以请你睡在这沙发吗?
...would you sleep on the sofa?
没问题
No problem.
晚安
Good night.
等等
Listen....
不怕你笑我老古板
At the risk of sounding old-fashioned...
我该知道你的真名吧?
...Isn't it time l knew your real name?
黛比萧
Darby Shaw.
你怎么会找上我?
What made you pick me   Darby Shaw?
可拉汉很欣赏你
Callahan was a fan.
维多马提斯这名字有印象吗?
does the name Victor Mattece mean anything to you?
金钱、
Money...
权利、
...power...
势力
...influence...
他在"南路易斯安那"
He's made and lost several fortunes
开发石油  大赚也大赔过
drilling for oil in south Louisiana.
1979年
in 1979...
他在特瑞拜
his oil company punched some holes in Terrebonne Parish and
发现石油
hit oil.
大量的石油
A lot of oil.
他需要政府批准
He needed governmental permission...
挖一条油管
To dredge a channel
穿过沼泽地
though the marshlands to get the oil out.
马提斯
Enter Mattece
因他是竞选献金大户
the great campaign contributor and as night follows day
所以政府批准了这条
Government permission to gouge through the
危害沼泽生态的油管
endangered marshes.
马提斯差点就赚了10亿
Mattece is that close to at least a billon dollars...
但绿色基金会
...when Green Fund...
一个不知名的环保组织
...an obscure environmental outfit...
到法拉叶
trots down to the U.S.
地方法院告了一状
district court in Lafayette and files a lawsuit
想阻止该工程
...to stop the entre operation.
马提斯不惜大派金钱
Of course   Mattece spares no expense to
只求胜诉
win the lawsuit.
我不相信
l don't think
从休斯顿到纽奥良  所有一流律师
there's a top law firm between Houston and New Orleans
都曾受他委托
that he hasn't hired.
该死的公视
Fucking PBS
绿色基金会仅有的两名律师
By the time the Green Fund lawyers  all two of them
奋力出击
wade in
但所有合资公司、
The joint ventures limited partnerships and
法人机构
corporate associations
早已筑起牢不可破的迷宫
form an impenetrable maze that makes Mattece invisible.
绿色基金会运气好
Luckily for the Green Fund's lawsuit...
油田中心
The heart of the new oil reserve is
靠近水鸟保护区
near a natural refuge for waterfowl
鹗、白鹭、塘鹅、鹤、鹅群集
Osprey   egrets   pelicans   ducks   cranes   geese.
塘鹅成了英雄
The pelican becomes the hero.
因30年来
After 30 years of
受杀虫剂的侵害
contamination by ddT and other pesticides
路易斯安那州的塘鹅面临绝种
the Louisiana brown pelican is on the brink of extinction.
绿色基金会抓住这个题材  召集
Green Fund seizes the bird and enlists
全国专家作证
experts from around the country to testify on its behalf.
花了7年才使案子
It takes 7 years for the pelican suit to go to
起诉
trial in Lake Charles.
但陪审团为了饭碗
The 3-man jury
不管塘鹅生死
caring less about the pelicans than jobs...
判马提斯胜诉
...votes in favor of Mattece.
所幸法官下了
But the judge rules to keep the
钻油禁令
injunction against drilling because
他认为绿色基金会
he thinks Green Fund has
说得有理
proven its point about the pelican...
塘鹅是联邦保护的稀有动物
...a federally-protected spices   and that it will appeal.
此案目前情况如何?
What's the lawsuit's status?
就审判而言
From the trial level...
1个月内上诉到
it will be appealed to
纽奥良法院
the Court of Appeals in New Orleans in a month.
法院会怎判?
Any idea what the court will do?
可能会翻案
it could be reversed.
那就有好戏看了
Then the fun starts.
只要任何一方不服判决
lf ether side s unhappy with the court...
都可能上诉到最高法院
...they can appeal to the Supreme Court.
从今天算起
From today
最高法院的判决要等多久?
how long would it take for a decision by the Supreme Court?
3到5年
Anywhere from 3 to 5 years.
那时罗森伯大概早死了
Rosenberg would have died.
他死时  白宫也可能易主了
But another president could be n the White House when he died.
若你是马提斯
So if you're Mattece...
也不在乎杀几个大法官
...and you don't mind killing a couple of Supremes...
杀了他们正是时候
now is the time to kill them
趁现在还能预测谁是接班人
when you can predict their replacement.
那为何杀杰生?
But why Jensen?
他和罗森伯站同一阵线
He shared one piece of common ground with Rosenberg
都是环保人士
Protecting the environment.
贾西亚
律师事务所
马提斯
白宫
我没吵醒你吧?
Didn't me wake you?
你说从
You sad that
休士顿到纽奥良  所有律师事务所  都受马提斯委托
Mattece hired law firms from Houston to New Orleans.
华府也有吗?
Were there any in Washington?
我想得出两家
Maybe two.
怀特暨布莱兹维屈公司
White & Blazevich...
和布林姆、史坦兹及某人
...and Brim   Stearns & Somebody.
好极了
Great!
我曾接到华府一个律师的电话
l got a call from a lawyer in D.C....
他说看过有关两个法官的资料
...who saw something concerning Rosenberg and Jensen.
但他临阵退缩
He backed out of our meeting.
不再与我联络
l never heard from him again.
他报假名  但我弄到他相片
He gave me a phony name   but l got his picture.
怎么弄的?
How?
说来话长  若他在其中一家上班
Long story. lf he works at one of these law firms
就可能是人证
he could be our confirmation.
我希望你能找到他
l hope you find hm.
和我一起去华府
Come with me to Washington.
不  我受够了
I've had enough.
若你猜中马提斯的事
lf you're right about Mattece
他们一定会掩护
then there'll be a cover-up.
很可能得逞
it'll probably work.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
昨晚从报社编政组资料室得知
l called the Herald morgue last night.
两年前  有记者写了一则报导
Two years ago   a reporter did a piece...
关于"违反竞选献金法"
...on ''Volitions of Campaign Financing Laws.''
记者发现
He found out that
马提斯利用许多个人、
hidden under a lot of other names of individuals
团体之名献金
and PAC's and corporations
其实是
Mattece was
总统竞选活动的最大金主
the biggest contributor by far to the President's campaign.
报导附带一张
We ran a picture   with the article
他与总统的合照
of the President and Mattece.
是偷拍的
It was taken unbeknownst to ether one.
总统与马提斯
in t   the President and Mattece
在狞猎屋前
are in front of Mattece's hunting
把酒言欢
lodgesipping on some bourbon   having a good laugh.
俨然最佳拍档
The best of pals.
标题是：总统最大的秘密
The captions sad: "The President's Most Secret
及最慷慨的赞助人
and Generous Contributor.''
若你推论正确
Now   if your brief is right
又能公之于世
and it ever reaches the light of day
总统就休想连任
the President loses any chance of reelection.
他身边的人必会阻止这种结果
The men around the President won't let that happen.
我问过CIA、FBI及
l checked with my sources. The Bureau   Langley
白宫内线
the White House
他们全否认有该档案
all sad the brief doesn't exist.
你可能是唯一的证人
You may be the only witness to the fact there is a brief.
若你失踪  正义也没了
lf you disappear so does justice.
可拉汉会希望这样吗?
Is that what Callahan would want?
他希望我过25岁生日
He'd want me to see my 25th birthday.
若这件事
lf this thing reaches as deep and
真的涉及了白宫高层
goes as high as we think it does
他们会不择手段  阻止东窗事发
They'll do anything not to be exposed.
你能躲到那去?
Where can you hide?
回华盛顿去
Go back to Washington.
你走来走去  他们紧张极了
They'll all shook up about you asking about something.
意料中事
l expected that.
白宫像盖世太保再现
it's like the Gestapo over there.
寇尔一手遮天
Coal clears everything.
他要我请90天病假
They put me on medical leave for 90 days.
你怎么了?
-What's wrong with you?
我也不知道  有件事我倒知道
l don't know.One thing l do know
白宫从不曾这么紧张过  我为你担心
I've never seen it this bad.I'm worried about you son.
格雷  我是黛比  你听到录音时
Gray   it's Darby.When you hear this
我已在空中
I'll be in the air on my way to nowhere.
不一定飞到那儿  请多谅解
Try to understand.
我不能让你再追这条新闻
l can't keep you on that story.
你去阿肯色州吧
I'm sending you to Arkansas.
时报和电视台都在那里
The Times   the networks are there
追踪可能提名的法官名单
checking out the judge they're about to nominate.
我还需要些时间
l need more time.
干嘛?你失去了白宫内线
For what? You lost your White House sources
那女孩和贾西亚也不见了  你这周的成绩不佳
you've lost Garcia and the girl.Not your best week.
你不能撤掉我这条新闻
You can't take me off this story.
你有何实证?
What do you know for fact?
某人说他知道暗杀的事
An unidentified guy says he knows about the assassinations.
他在律师事务所上班
He works in a law firm
你不知那家  他又不再联络
You don't know which one. He's cut off all contact.
实在没啥搞头
That's not very promising.
这里面大有文章  我闻得到
There's something there   l can smell it.
根据嗅觉发现的证据  是不能被接受的
Evidence based on olfactory prowess is inadmissible
容我提醒你
in case you didn't know.
还有那女孩子
Then there's a girl...
带着你无法证实的狗屎文章
with her bird brief for which you can't get confirmation.
还说不定
Yet.
是  但她已失去踪影
She also cut off contact
失踪像会传染一样
something that's reaching epidemic proportions.
他们在楼上等你
They're waiting for you upstarts.
好的
All right
她说的两宗命案不是
Everything she sad about the two deaths
证实了吗?
has been confirmed.
但FBI说维西在旅馆遇害
The FBl says Verheek was killed n some hotel mugging.
这是你告诉我的
-That's what you told me.
这是他们告诉我的
-That's what they told me.
他们否认
And they sad they knew of no
与暗杀有关
connection with the assassinations.
他们还会怎么说?
-What else would they say?
我只管他们怎么说
-I'm interested in what they did say.
谈谈我证实的东西
Let's look at what l have confirmed.
可拉汉被炸死
Callahan was killed in a car explosion.
他们是一对恋人
They had an affair.
拿给明星报了
Give it to the Times-Picayune.
也许他们需要娱乐新闻
Maybe they want some gossip.
我还发现
l also found that
20年前  可拉汉当过罗森伯的书记
Callahan clerked for Rosenberg 20 years ago.
人生充满奇妙的巧合
Life is filled with odd coincidence.
都与报告有关就不是巧合
Not a coincidence if the brief--
你无法证实这份报告
you have no confirmation there is a brief.
我已确知维西和可拉汉是知交
l confirmed Verheek and Callahan were friends.
几周前他们在华府见过面
They met here a few weeks ago
可拉汉一定把报告给了维西
when he must have given him the brief.
又是推测
-Supposition again.
塘鹅案确有其事
-I've confirmed the pelican lawsuit.
她就是根据这件案子做的推测
On which she has based her suppositions.
全是推测
it's all just suppositions.
你晓得马提斯会怎样对付我们?
you know what Mattece could do?
我知道他怎样对付别人
l know what he has done already.
他有一段不可告人的历史
He has a bizarre history.
我前妻也这样说我
So do l   according to my ex-wife.
但不表示我杀了这些法官
it doesn't mean that l killed the Justices.
但这表示有必要追查
But it means it's worth exploring.
好了  你何不回到你那狗窝去
Go down to that crappy cabin of yours on the weekend
把事情想个清楚?
hole up   retrench.
若证明有办法起死回生
Prove you have a way to revitalize this story
你就继续查了
and l might keep you on it.
不过若我是你
But if l were you
我会去打听小岩城内那里有小吃
I'd check where to eat in Little Rock.
这故事可能是个
This is the story of a mystery that
不解之谜
may never be solved.
故事中的年轻律师
The story of a brilliant young lawyer
热爱大地
who loved this land...
奋力保护它免受
...and wanted to fight to preserve it from
人类侵害
the inroads of man...
直到数月前  他摔死
...until his abrupt death a few months ago.
尸体在一间孤寂的木屋中发现
His body was found in a lonely cottage
就在他热爱的湖畔
near the bayou he so loved.
他头部中枪
There was a bullet in his head...
身旁有一把枪
...and a gun beside him.
警方、法医认定是自杀
The coroner and police have deemed it a suicide.
但他死在电脑前
But he died sitting at a computer
周围散落着笔记
surrounded by his notes...
内容是这件他自称必羸的案子
...for what he called the case he was born to win.
他的亲友质问：
Hs friends and family ask...
谁会在这种时候
...would anyone commit suicide in
以这种方式自杀?
such a manner at such a time?
今晚  头条新闻将探讨
Tonight   Frontline explores the death of
一个年轻理想主义者之死
a young idealist.
谁在外面?
Who's there?
我是黛比
it's Darby!
谢谢
Thank
我听到你的留言
l got your message.
若他们窃听你的电话
lf they bugged your phone
会以为我已出国
l wanted them to think l left the country.
你找到华府那个律师了吗?
Did you find that lawyer in D.C.?
还没有
Not yet.
主编要我停止追查
My editor wants to take me off the story.
我能帮你找到他
l could help you find him.
你怎么找到我的?
How'd you find me?
我问你的编辑
l called your editor.
他就告诉你了?
He told you?
我说我是你妹妹玛丽
l told him l was your sister Mary
从外地来找不到你
from out of town and couldn't find you.
你怎知我有个妹妹叫玛丽?
How'd you know l had a sister Mary?
不是只有你去做功课
You're not the only one dong research.
这是很成功的告别式
It was a beautiful service.
谢谢你  总统先生
Thank you   Mr president
周末后  我会做一项宣布
I'll have an announcement after the weekend.
这是明智之举
It was the right thing to do
不管尸体是在哪里找到的
no matter where the body was found.
下周还不能公布法官名单
You can't announce the nominations next week.
不是说周末就完成财产调查?
you sad they'd be vetted this weekend.
不  计划有变了
There must be a change in plans.
我不明白
l don't understand.
塘鹅档案
The Pelican Brief.
又怎么了?
What about the Pelican Brief?
我认为那已是过去的事了
l thought that was ancient history.
我们认为葛瑞还在穷追不舍
We believe that Grantham's gotten a hold of it.
若见报  马提斯会告他们
Mattece will sue the pants off them if they try to publish that.
若是事实呢?
Not if it's true.
你认为是真的?
you think it's true?
我知道葛瑞会这样写
l know what Grantham will write:
给总统百万金钱的人
"A man who gave the President millions...
杀了两名大法官
had two Supreme Court Justices killed
好让他的至友总统
So his pal   the President
提名更通情达理的法官
could appoint more reasonable men to the bench
让他开采石油
so that his oil could be harvested."
若伏尔说出你叫他放弃调查
lf Voyles says you told him to back off the case
我们会负上"妨害司法罪"
we face an obstruction charge.
该死 没错
Oh   Jesus!
有个办法能解决
There's a way to handle this.
什么办法?
Handle it how?
提名两个热衷环保的法官
We appoint two nature-lovers to the court.
他们会解决马提斯
Good environmentalists who'd kill Mattece and
控油管之事
his oil field.
再当着首席大法官的面
Meet with Voyles   in the presence of the Attorney General
命令伏尔立即调查马提斯
...and demand an immediate investigation into Mattece.
我再把报告走漏给记者们
I'll leak copes of the brief to every reporter in town.
我们就可解脱了
Then we ride out the storm.
但得想办法
But there has to be some way to
不让风声走漏
keep this information from coming out.
我正在想办法
I'm working on t.
什么办法?怎么做?
What? How?
总统先生
Mr. President...
你还是不知道为好
...you don't want to know.
这是干嘛?
What's this all about?
到维农山走走对你有益
A trip to Mt. Vernon will do you good.
你疯了?
Are you losing t?
我叫你去小岩城
First l order you to go to Little Rock
你不去
you refuse to go.
既不说原因  还命令我
you refuse to tell me why   then you order me...
你的上司
Your boss
于百忙中跑
l might add to drop everything and meet you
来华盛顿故乡
at George's place.
我真想炒你鱿鱼
l thought of making you unemployed...
但你会告我种族歧视
...but you'd sue me for discrimination.
她在这里
She's here.
那鸟女孩?她在这里
-The bird girl? -She's here.
你早告诉我嘛
You could've told me.
那不好 还有呢
Not wise.By the way
拒绝透露你的联络处
refusing to tell me where you could be reached...
让我对你印像极差
...didn't leave a good impression.
回我公寓或报社  都太危险
it's too risky to go to my apartment or to the job.
那你住那? 一家小旅馆
-Where have you been? -in a little hotel.
现在不是寻欢作乐的时候
This is a hell of a time to punch notches in your belt.
我们不住同一房
We're not in the same hotel.
她在帮我找贾西亚
She's helping me find Garcia.
听起来好像她在掌控
it sounds like she's in control.
只有这样  她才肯帮忙
it's the only way she'd play.
若找不到贾西亚呢?
So what if you can't find Garcia?
我们就用B计划
-We go to plan B.
那是什么?
-What's that?
我们直捣律师事务所
-We attack the lawyers directly.
若是别家律师事务所呢?
-What if it's another firm?
那就用C计划
-We go to plan C.
那又是什么?
-What's that?
我们还没想出来
-We didn't go that far.
若想出来了呢?
-What if you do?
我一定要能跟你联系
l must be able to get in touch with you.
马伯利饭店833室  别用我名字
I'm at the Marbury Hotel   room 833. Don't use my name.
写下来
Write it down.
麻烦下个出口转弯
you mind getting off at the next ext?
为何?
Why?
隔两部车后面  有辆茶色汽车
A tan car's been two cars behind us...
从我们上这条路就一直跟着
...since we got on the parkway.
我以为是跟踪我们
l thought it was following us.
可不是
Right.
乔治城法学院
Georgetown Law School   please.
开快点
Hurry.
书架旁见
Meet me by the stacks.
有人潜入我房间
Someone was in my room.
你跟谁说过你住的地方?
Did you tell anyone where you were?
史密斯金  他不会泄露
Smith Keen   but he'd never repeat t.
你是在电话上说的?
Did you tell him by phone?
不
We were....
在他车上
We were in his car.
乔治城法学中心
-Georgetown Law Center.
请接职业介绍处
-Placement office   please.
请稍候
-One moment   please.
职业介绍处
-Placement office.
我叫苏珊强生
This is Susan Johnson.
怀特暨布莱兹维屈公司律师  公司电脑有故障
I'm a partner with White & Blazevich.
我们想重建薪资档案
We're trying to reconstruct some payroll records.
需要贵校
May l have the names of your students that
去年夏天实习的学生名单
clerked here last summer?
我是怀特暨布莱兹维屈公司的人  有东西给我吗?
I'm from White & Blazevich. you have something for me?
谢谢
Thank you
请在这里签名
Would you sign this   please?
谢谢你  史蒂文先生
-Thank you   Mr. Stevens.
不客气
-y you're welcome.
我打这5个  看他们是否在家
I'll call these 5 and see who's home.
我找这两个
I'll take the two with
没电话学生的课程表
no phone number and get their class schedules.
等会见
See you later.
我是前锋报记者  格雷葛瑞
I'm Gray Grantham from the Washington Herald.
我找
I'm looking for...
罗勃阿克司和罗拉凯斯
-...Robert Akers and Laura Kaas.
出什么事了?
-is there a problem?
没事  只是问些问题
Just a few questions l want to ask.
他们在上课吗?
Are they in class this morning?
请稍等
One moment   please.
对不起
Excuse me.
你有证件吗?
Do you have I.D.?
请问丹尼梅勒在吗?
Could l speak to Dennis Maylor   please?
不  我是济斯梅勒
I'm Keith Maylor.
对不起  打错了
I'm sorry to bother you.
在家  济斯梅勒
阿克司在上刑事程序学
Akers has Criminal Procedure.
凯斯从9点到10点  上行政法课
Kaas has Administrative Law on both 9 and 10.
我会找他们
I'll try to find them. Maylor
雷和威都在家
Renhart and Wilson were all at home.
我去梅勒家
l can go to Maylor's.
请问
Excuse me.
你认识罗拉凯斯吗?
-Do you know Laura Kaas?
那个背红背包的女孩就是  谢谢
-She's the girl with the red backpack.
你认得这个人吗?
Do you recognize this man?
他是怀特暨布莱兹维屈的律师吗?
He's a lawyer at White & Blazevich.
只剩下阿克司和蓝尼了
We're down to Akers and Linney.
蓝尼的电话不通
Linney's phone was disconnected.
我去找他的课程表
I'll get his class schedule.
我继续找阿克司
I'll keep looking for Akers.
嗨  又是我
it's me again.
我需要爱德华蓝尼的课程表
l need the class schedule for Edward Linney.
很抱歉  葛先生
I'm sorry   Mr. Grantham.
跟你说过话的一个学生
One of the students you talked to
打电话给律师事务所  他们和教务长联络过
called White & Blazevich   who called the Dean.
不能再给记者课程表了
No more class schedules for reporters.
葛先生
Mr. Grantham.
我认识爱德华
l know Edward.
他暂时休学  有个人问题
He's dropped out of school for a while. Personal problems.
他在那里?
Where is he?
他父母送他去私人医院
Hs parents put him n a private hospital.
他正在戒毒
He's being detoxified.
他是个好人
Look   he's a good guy.
他在巴克联医院
Parklane Hospital.
巴克联医院
午安
Good afternoon.
我来看爱德华蓝尼
I'm here to see Edward Linney.
他病房几号?
-What room is he n?
你贵姓大名?
-What's your name?
我是格雷葛瑞  前锋报
Gray Grantham   Washington Herald.
学校说我能见他
The law school sad l could see hm.
很抱歉他们这么说
I'm sorry they dd.
医院归我们管  学校归他们管
We run this hospital and they run their law school.
我能见院长吗?
May l see your administrator?
我看能不能找到他
I'll see if l can find hm.
葛先生?
Mr. Grantham?
很棒的建筑 是啊
Great architecture. Yes
抱歉  葛先生
I'm sorry   Mr. Grantham.
会客只限周未
Visitation is only allowed on the weekend.
只有家属能探访
And then only family.
他何时出院?
When will he be discharged?
抱歉  这要保密
I'm afraid that's confidential.
或许等到他保险到期吧?
Perhaps when his insurance express?
你认识这个人吗?
Do you recognize that man?
他叫什么名字?
What's his name?
这就是我想知道的
That's the point   l don't know.
他叫什么了?
What is his name?
他在9楼的石油和天然气部门
He works in the oil and gas section on the 9th floor.
摩根
Morgan.
对  就是摩根
名字好像是……查尔士
Hs first name's something like Charles
但不是很确定
but that's not t.
感激不尽
l can't tell you how grateful l am.
不  你打开房门时
When you opened the door
我以为是幻觉
l thought l was hallucinating.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
不  我喜欢那样美丽的幻觉
I'll take a hallucination like that
随时欢迎
Anytime.
保重了
Take care of yourself.
对不起  小姐  你在这里干嘛?
Excuse me   mis.What're you dong?
看我弟弟
Visiting my brother.
谁是你弟弟?
Who is your brother?
爱德华蓝尼
Edward Linney.
这是你姐姐?
This your sister?
是啊  让她走
Leave her alone.
妈妈周未会来看你
Mom will come on the weekend.
姐  快点来
Sister   come back soon.
我尽量
I'll try.
你知道医疗
l know you'd agree with me about
成本贵得惊人
the horrendous cost of health care.
当然、当然
Of course   of course.
本院收费
We pride ourselves on our
政策开明  非常自豪
enlightened policy regarding payment.
谢谢你宝贵的时间
Thank you very much for your time.
欢迎你在
We'll be happy to have you back on any of
会客时间光临
our normal visiting days.
寇蒂斯摩根  石油天然气部门
Curtis Morgan   oil and gas.
请问  怀特暨布莱兹维屈公司在几楼?
White & Blazevich   please.
2楼  搭电梯
Second floor. Use the escalator.
能为你效劳吗?
May l help you?
桃乐丝布莱  找寇蒂斯摩根
Dorothy Blythe   to see Curtis Morgan.
请坐  我马上回来
Have a seat. I'll be right with you.
布莱小姐  你和摩根有约?
You have a meeting with Mr. Morgan?
是的  5点
Yes   at five.
何时订的约?
When did you make the appointment?
两周前
2 weeks ago.
有什么事吗?
May l ask why?
我需要一个懂石油天然气的律师
Obviously   l need an oil and gas lawyer.
寇蒂斯摩根  死了
Curtis Morgan is dead.
为何没通知我?
Why didn't anyone call me?
我们没你订约的记录
We have no record of your appointment.
他怎么死的?
What happened?
他在一周前遭劫杀
He was mugged a week ago.
被街头混混开枪打死
Shot by street punks   we believe.
你有证件吗?
Do you have some identification?
他是安检人员
He's Security.
安检什么?
Security for what?
跟我们来  你该见另一位律师
Come with us   you should see someone else.
如此对待客户
After this treatment
我不想再与你们谈了
l have no interest in talking to anyone in this firm.
他们杀了他
They killed him!
我喘不过气、我喘不过气
l can't breathe!
不要紧  哭吧  大声哭吧
It's all right. Just let it go. Let it go.
没事了
It's all right.
一周前登过新闻
We ran the story about a week ago.
只是抢劫案
it's just another mugging.
连上地方版也不够资格
Didn't make the Metro front page.
寇蒂斯摩根  贝塞斯达  柳树路225号
Curtis Morgan  225 Willows Road   Bethesda.
柳树路225号  贝塞斯达  正是我要的
225 Willows Road   Bethesda. That's what l wanted.
明天中午前报到
Report in before noon tomorrow.
我们很赶
We're nervous over here.
你知道  好手难找
You know   good help is hard to find.
我跟你去
I'm gong with you.
看着我
Look at me.
我要你出国
l want you to leave.
万一你需要证人呢?
And if you need confirmation for your story?
我自己来
I'm on my own.
你为何改变主意?
What's changed your mind?
我要你活到25岁
l want you to reach 25.
我要跟你去
I'm coming.
这是安.  幸会
This is Anne. Nice to meet you.
晚上好. 有什么事吗?
Good evening. Yes?
我是华盛顿前锋报的葛瑞
I'm Grantham of the Herald.
这是我助手  能见摩根太太吗?
This is my assistant. Could we see Mrs. Morgan?
我是她爸  她不见访客
I'm her father. She won't talk.
我尊重她的隐私
l respect her privacy.
我知道她很难过
l know she's been through an ordeal.
你们何时有尊重过别人的隐私?
When did you people ever respect anyone's privacy?
的确很多记者很恶劣
l feel that way about most reporters.
但她丈夫曾给我电话
But her husband called me
在他死前  与我通过3次电话
three times before he died.
我不相信他是意外死亡
l don't believe his death was accidental.
她不想谈  你们走吧
She doesn't want to talk. Get the hell out of here.
若你改变心意  打这个电话找我
You change your mind   I'll be at this number.
喂?
Yes?
葛瑞先生?
Mr. Grantham?
对. 我是摩根太太
Yes. This is Mrs. Morgan.
葛瑞先生   你还想见我吗?
Mr. Grantham  do you still want to see me?
你知道你丈夫曾给我电话?
Did you know your husband called me?
不知道
No
他怎会知道暗杀法官的事?
How would he know anything about those dead judges?
我也不知道
l have no idea.
他是否……保存什么特殊文件、或报告?
Did he keep any...unusual documents or papers?
银行有个保险箱  存放契约文件
We have a lock box at the bank for deeds and wills.
上周四我查过
l looked at it last Thursday.
没特殊文件
There was nothing unusual in it.
周六早上
On Saturday morning
我整理卧室的书桌
l was gong through his desk in the bedroom.
发现一样不寻常的东西
l found something a bit unusual.
一把锁匙
A key.
什么锁匙?
A key to what?
另一个保险箱的
Another lock box.
那家银行?
Which bank?
雷克银行  我们从没在这银行开过户
Riggs Bank. We've never banked there.
你毫不知道有另一个保险箱?
And you knew nothing about this other box?
直到周六早上才知道
Not until Saturday morning.
我是想  等我心情好点才去查
l figured   I'll run by when l felt up to it.
也许你真要查一下   摩根太太
Maybe you should check it   Mrs. Morgan.
有可能找到凶手的线索
Could be a clue to who killed hm.
你是说  寇蒂斯被杀
Are you saying Curtis was killed
是因为他知道暗杀法官的内幕?
because he knew something about these assassinations?
一点没错
That's exactly what I'm saying.
你认为
Do you think
保险箱里会有文件
there may be papers in the safe deposit box that
透露寇蒂斯知道的暗杀内幕?
may reveal what Curtis knew about the assassinations?
有可能
There could be.
我的孩子已失去了父亲
My child's lost one parent.
不能让她再失去母亲
l can't let her lose another.
我可帮你去查
I'll check it for you.
没人会知道你有锁匙的事
No one has to know you have the key.
只有他太太才能开保险箱
They will only give it to his wife.
我的拍档是个女人  她靠得住
My partner's a woman. She's trustworthy.
有一个条件
l would have one condition.
若有任何
lf you find something that
不利我先生的资料
disparages my husband in any way
你不能用
you can't use t.
我保证  摩根太太
You have my word   Mrs. Morgan.
请问保险箱库往那走?
Where are the safe deposit boxes?
下楼梯   谢谢
Down those steps. Thank you
我要开保险箱
l need access to a box   please.
几号?616
-The number   please? -616.
保险箱是两周前租的
This box was rented 2 weeks ago.
对
Yes
你是摩根太太?
l assume you're Mrs. Morgan?
莎拉安摩根
Sara Ann Morgan.
住址是?
The address?
贝塞斯达  柳树路225路
225 Willows Road   Bethesda.
电话号码?301-555-7128
Phone number? 301-555-7128.
是谁租的?
Who rented this box?
我先生  寇蒂斯摩根
My husband   Curtis D. Morgan.
他的社会保险卡号码?
And his social security number?
510-96-8686
请在这签名
Will you sign here   please?
我可效劳吗?
May l help you?
我想租个保险箱
I'd like to rent a box.
请坐  我马上过来
Will you have a seat? I'll be with you in a minute.
谢谢
Thank you
有锁匙吗?
your key?
有
Yes   l do.
跟我来
Follow me.
这是共4页的口供状  经过宣誓签名的
It's a four-page affidavit   signed under oath.
日期是最后一次通电话的前一天
It's dated the day before the last time he called me.
他在石油
He worked at White & Blazevich in the oil and
天然气部门工作了
gas section for
5年
5 years.
听这个
Listen to this!
当时有个客户
During that time   he worked for a client who
涉及路易斯安那州一件诉讼案
was engaged in a lawsuit in Louisiana.
客户叫维多马提斯
The client was a man named Victor Mattece
他们从未谋面
who he's never met.
这里有许多诉讼内情
Lots about the lawsuit
马提斯不顾一切要打羸官司
how desperate Mattece was to win it.
就如你猜想的一样
Just as if you wrote it.
一个叫西姆伟克菲的律师
A partner named Sims Wakefield
替公司承办这案子
supervised the case for W & B.
摩根在办一件犯罪案子
Morgan worked on a perpetrated case.
摩根负责另外一个案子
He took files and documents that
他拿了伟克菲留给他的文件
Wakefield left for him is not related to the case
回到自己办公室后才发现
When he got back to his own offic
文件底下有张手写的备忘录
he found a handwritten memo on the bottom of the stack.
他是无意中从伟克菲桌上拿的
He'd inadvertently taken t from Wakefield's desk.
备忘录副本附在口供状中
A copy of the memo is attached to the affidavit.
他影印了备忘录
He coped the memo and
正本放回原来的卷宗内
left the memo under the files on his desk.
下一站  华盛顿前锋报
Next stop   Washington Herald!
停  快下车
Stop! Get out of the car!
雷克银行附近发生汽车爆炸案
There was a car explosion n a garage near the Riggs Bank.
警察找到租车公司
The police traced the car to a leasing agency.
车子是葛瑞昨天租的
It was rented yesterday by Grantham.
有他消息吗?
Have you heard from Grantham?
从昨天起就没消息
Not since yesterday.
我应该阻止他追查这条新闻的
l should've taken him off that story.
什么新闻?
What story?
去看看能查出什么
See what you can find.
史密斯金  这是黛比萧
Smith Keen   meet Darby Shaw.
到底怎么回事?
What the hell is gong on?
亲爱的  我在地下室
Sweetheart   I'm down here in the basement
现在大约是凌晨2点
it's about two in the morning.
这是一份宣誓书
This is an affidavit
有关我发现的一张备忘录
concerning a memo l found on my desk.
你怎么处理它都行  我信任你
I'm gong to trust you to do with it what you will.
这是资深合伙人法曼诺写的
The memo's from Velmano   he's a senor partner.
日期是9月28日
It was dated September 28th
字条是写给伟克菲的  内容是：
addressed to Wakefield and it read:
"西姆  通知客户研究已完成
"Sims   advise client research is complete.
若老人退休  法官席较安稳
The bench will sit much softer if the old man is retired.
第二名退休者较不寻常
The second retirement is a bit unusual.
居然是杰生
Jensen   of all people.
考虑其他因素
Advise further that
塘鹅案应在
the pelican should arrive here in
4年内递交最高法院"
4 years assuming other factors."
上面没有签名
There's no signature.
之后罗森伯和杰生法官即被杀
Then Justices Rosenberg and Jensen were killed.
我坚信这是
l firmly believe that this is the work of
马提斯一伙人干的
Mattece and his associates.
字条上没指名是马提斯
Memo doesn't mention Mattece
但指名是要给一位客户
but it refers to a client.
除了他  没有其他客户.
Wakefield had no other clients.
能从更换法官中获利更大
And no client had as much to gain from the new court.
本以为我不说出来
l thought that l was protecting us by not revealing
一切就没事
what l found.
若我死了
You'll only see this if I'm gone
表示我已失败.
so l will have failed.
对不起  亲爱的
I'm sorry   sweetheart.
我永远在你身边
I'll always be with you.
永远
Always.
我是麦地法曼诺
This is Marty Velmano. What a pleasure!
有何需要效劳?
What can l do for you?
我们将刊登马提斯的新闻
We're dong a story about Victor Mattece
有关他涉疑罗森伯与杰生之死
and his involvement in the deaths of Rosenberg and Jensen.
好极了
Great!
我们会告你们20年
We'll sue you for the next 20 years
你将成为被告
you'll be named as a defendant.
哦  真是太好了
Oh   this will be great.
马提斯会把前锋报吃下来
Victor Mattece will own the Herald.
你听过塘鹅档案吗?
Have you heard of the Pelican Brief?
我们有份副本
We have a copy of it.
还有一张
We also have a copy of a memo
你给西姆伟克菲的备忘录副本
sent by you to Sims Wakefield...
上面提到
In which you suggest
要改善客户目前的处境
your client's position would be greatly improved
必须除去罗森伯和杰生
by the removal of Rosenberg and Jensen from the court.
你要等到5点才可刊登
l noticed you waited till five.
但1小时后
An hour earlier
我们能到法院阻止它见报
we could've run to court   stopped this.
你否认写了这张备忘录?
You deny you wrote the memo?
那是捏造的
It's a fabrication.
你没法告我们  法曼诺先生  你心知肚明
You have no lawsuit   Mr. Velmano. you know it.
混蛋
You son-of-a-bitch!
寇尔先生  你看过塘鹅档案吧?
Mr. Coal? Have you read the Pelican Brief?
看过
l have.
我们将刊登报导已
We're running a story which
证实的档案内容
verifies the facts set forth in that brief.
我们证实马提斯捐了400万
We've confirmed Mattece contributed over $4 million
赞助总统这一任的竞选活动
to the President's last campaign.
420万美元  都是经过合法的管道
4  200  000   all through legal channels.
对
That's right.
但我们相信
We believe the
白宫曾妨碍FBI调查
White House tried to obstruct the FBl investigation and
不知你有没意见?
we wonder if there are any comments.
白宫否认任何直接、
The White House denies any direct
或间接干预
or indirect involvement
你的消息来源不对
you've received some bad information.
伏尔先生  葛瑞  华盛顿前锋报什么事?
Mr. Voyles   it's Grantham.
我们正要报导一项阴谋
We're running a story detailing a conspiracy
事关罗森伯和杰生被杀内幕
in the murders of Rosenberg and Jensen.
我们点名大石油商马提斯
We're naming Mattece   an oil speculator
及他的两名律师
and two of his lawyers.
我们认为FBI知情
We believe the FBl knew about Mattece
但因白宫施压而没调查
but didn't investigate at the urging of the White House.
不知你有何评论?
Any comments?
我认为事情一定圆满
l think we'll have great success with these people.
我们都很高兴
They were really very pleased and
合作愉快
genuinely cooperative.
什么事?
What's up?
你认识的格雷葛瑞
You know Gray Grantham.
这是黛比萧
And this is Darby Shaw.
你就是搞得
So you're the little lady
天下大乱的小女生?
who started this great brouhaha.
你别把我
l think you have me confused
与总统归为一类
with the President's friend.
我有话要说
l have some comments for the record.
你可引用  两周前……
First   we got the Pelican Brief two weeks ago
两周前  我们收到塘鹅档案  当天就呈交白宫
and submitted it to the White House on the same day.
原先没把它当作优先调查案件
It was not considered high priority in the investigation
直到首席律师葛文维西
until Gavin Verheek Special Counsel to the Director
被杀
was found murdered.
白宫是否施压、
Did the White House interfere
并干预调查马提斯?
in the FBl investigation of Mattece?
我能谈这件事  但内容不可公开
I'll discuss it off the record.
上周三
Last Wednesday
总统要我
the President asked me to
放弃调查马提斯
ignore Victor Mattece as a suspect.
引用他的话  他要我"撒手"
In his words   he asked me to "back off."
我这有个带子  现在还不能公开
l have a tape which l will allow no one to hear
除非总统先否认我刚才所言
unless the President first denies this.
你现在怎么打算?
So what do you do now?
明天中午会组成大陪审团
There'll be a grand jury by noon tomorrow.
很快就会起诉
Quick indictments.
我们会捉到马提斯
And we'll find Mattece.
我想和萧小姐单独谈谈
I'd like a few minutes alone with Ms. Shaw.
若她愿意
lf she doesn't mind.
看她肯不肯了
It's her call.
我希望葛瑞留下
I'd like Mr. Grantham to stay.
你下一步怎么打算?
What's next for you?
是谁杀了伪装维西的人?
Who killed the man disgusted as Verheek?
哦  你指的是暗杀凶手凯莫
Oh   you mean the assassin   Khamel. Off the record
他是CIA私下
Khamel was killed by
请的杀手所杀
a contract operative hired independently by the ClA.
他叫鲁伯特?
Rupert?
他大概有20个化名
He probably has 20 names.
他为何跟踪她?
Why was he following her?
这档案最初
l think the brief initially
让格明斯最害怕
scared Gminsk more than anyone.
可能是他派鲁伯特跟踪黛比萧
And he probably sent Rupert to trial Darby.
一方面监视  一方面保护她
In part to watch and in part to protect.
我们可帮你  你有何要求?
We can help. What do you want?
我要单独离开这个国家
To leave the country   alone.
可以
All right.
我会护送你搭我私人飞机
We'll get you out of this building
送你去任何你想去的地方
put you on my plane. We'll fly you anywhere you want
你可以从此消失
And you can disappear.
但你要让我
But you must allow me to
透过葛瑞找得到你
contact you through Mr. Grantham.
真有必要我才会找你
If   and only if   it becomes urgently necessary.
同意
That's fine.
机上只能有我、葛瑞、飞行员
l want no one on the plane but me   Gray and the plots.
起飞后我会告诉飞行员去那
After take off   I'll tell the plot where to go.
可是  不交出航程表  他不能起飞的
He has to file a flight plan before he can leave.
你是FBI头子  安排一下了
You're the Director of the FBl. Set it up.
"暗杀内幕暴光"
葛瑞、黛比萧联合撰文
今天我们请到葛瑞
Our guest today is Gray Grantham
这位家喻户晓的人物
who has   as just about everyone in America knows
他揭发了
revealed the plot behind the
罗森伯和杰生凶案内幕
assassinations of Rosenberg and Jensen.
这新闻至今余波未平
The ripple effects of this story just don't seem to stop.
目前
As of this broadcast
美国首富维多马提斯
Victor Mattece   one of the country's richest men
连同4名助理和律师皆被起诉
has been indicted   along with 4 aides and lawyers.
总统幕僚长寇尔已辞职
Fletcher Coal   the President's Chef of Staff
迹象显示
has resigned. And we're getting strong indications that
总统将不再竞选连任
the President himself will not run again.
以上是我们知道的事  现在谈谈我们不知道的事
That's what we know. Let's get to what we don't.
据了解  "塘鹅档案"是
We know the Pelican Brief was
一位叫黛比萧的小姐所写
written by a woman named Darby Shaw
但我们不知道她是谁?谁是黛比萧?
But we don't know who that is. Who is Darby Shaw?
这问题要问黛比萧
That's a question for Darby Shaw.
既然如此  还有一问
That leads me to my next question.
是帮渴望
Speaking for many of our colleagues
访问她的同事代问
who are in a feeding frenzy to interview her
黛比萧在那?
where is Darby Shaw?
这还是要问黛比萧
That's also a question for Darby Shaw.
但她现在没空回答
But she's not available to answer questions
等访问热潮冷却再说
until the feeding frenzy stops.
这表示你不知她在那里?
Does that mean you don't know where she is?
我没这么说
l didn't say that.
那你是知道咯?
Then you do know.
我看你这诡异的笑容
l take it this cryptic smile means
就知道你不会回答了
you're not answering.
好吧  你知道吗?
In view of all this
有人猜测
you know that there's speculation  that
这女人是你杜撰的人物
this woman is a figment of your imagination.
是组合许多内线虚构出来的
That you created her from a lot of different sources.
有人相信
Just as there are people who believe
水门案中没有X先生
there was no Deep Throat.
同样  本案也没黛比萧此人
There are those who believe there is no Darby Shaw.
因她太完美  不可能真有其人
In other words   she's just too good to be true
她几乎没有缺点
She almost is.
谢谢观赏